ESLAM KHALIL

Flutter Developer

eslamkhalil920@gmail.com

◆ Egypt, Damanhour

+201007191997

GitHub: https://github.com/Eslamkhalil, LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/islam-khalil-919278b2/

Objective

4+ years of experiences developing Flutter-based mobile applications, increasing usability by 30%, driving 50% user engagement increase, and boosting sales by 40%. Optimized performance of Flutter app resulting in 300% increase in downloads in 6 months and developed a cross-platform Flutter app in 2 months, resulting in 40% cost savings.

Work Experience

Mid Flutter Developer - Full Time istoria , Saudi arabia.

Oct2023-Present

Flutter Developer - Full Time iksib Business Solutions, Kuwait.

August 2021- July 2023

Flutter Developer Freelancer Fab 2020 - August 2021

1. Code Implementations and Updates:

 Collaborated with cross-functional teams on projects, contributing to the implementation and update of lines of code using Flutter and Dart.

2. Daily Team Meetings:

• Engaged in daily team meetings to foster task alignment and boost team productivity.

3. Client Interaction:

 Collaborated with Business Analysts to comprehend client requirements, leading to successful project outcomes.

4. Unit Testing:

Implemented rigorous unit testing protocols for every task, achieving a defect-free rate of, ensuring robust and reliable code.

5. Architectural Patterns:

 Utilized MVVM, MVC, and JSON architectural patterns in the development of apps and app updates, resulting in improved code maintainability and scalability.

6. Design Integration:

 Proficiently converted designs from Figma and Adobe XD into functional Android applications, ensuring precise alignment and timely project delivery.

Latest Projects

Project title: Istoria

Project Outline: It is the most effective application for learning and developing the English language with both fun and simplicity. It expands your vocabulary to more than 3,000 words through some certified stories and starts from your level until you achieve professionalism anytime and anywhere in a unique and unprecedented way.

Technical Skills: - Clean arch - MVVM Pattern - Rest APi - json - SharedPreferences localizations - Ethir - provider(State Management) -

Project title: Glitch Store

Project Outline: Glitch Store is a mobile gaming platform that provides users with an effortless way to purchase in-game items, top-ups, and other gaming essentials.

Technical Skills: - Clean arch - MVVM Pattern - Rest APi - json - SharedPreferences localizations - Ethir - getx(State Management) - Connection checker - hive

Achievements: Google Play

Project title: Platinum Health Club

Project Outline: Platinum Health Club members can use this handy mobile application to purchase new memberships, upgrade and pause memberships, book new private classes, and much more. This application will help members manage their subscriptions on-the-go without having to visit the allocated branch.

Technical Skills: - Clean arch - oneSignal - MVVM Pattern - Rest APi - json - SharedPreferences

localizations - Ethir - Bloc (State Management) - Connection checker

Achievements: Google Play - App Store

Project title: Tarfih Rent App

Project Outline: A booking app built with Api in flutter is a mobile app that lets user book an entertainment place using api to retrieve products informations ,

Technical Skills: -Getx - Firebase -localNotifications - MVC Pattern - Rest APi - Maps - json - SharedPreferences

Achievements: Google Play - AppStore

Project title: Bahar App

Project Outline: a system that includes the environment of workers and contractors in the West Bank and inside the Green Line, works with high accuracy in the general accounts of the added projects and workers in order to completely eliminate errors in the accounts. And the ability to disclose accounts at any time.

Technical Skills: - Bloc -localNotifications - MVVM Pattern - Rest APi - Json - SharedPreferences,

Achievements: Google Play - AppStore

Project title: Leenoda

Project Outline: Revamped the FluxStore shopping app using Flutter and Firebase, executing a comprehensive redesign of the user interface to enhance the shopping experience and boost sales by 40% within 3 months.

Technical Skills: I redesigned the application and implemented extensive configuration changes, adding new features tailored to meet specific user requirements.

Achievements: Google Play - AppStore

Project title: Pet Store

Project Outline: Revamped the FluxStore shopping app using Flutter and Firebase, executing a comprehensive redesign of the user interface to enhance the shopping experience and boost sales by 40% within 3 months.

Technical Skills: I redesigned the application and implemented extensive configuration changes, adding new features tailored to meet specific user requirements.

Achievements: Google Play - AppStore

Project title: Freej Swaeleh

Project Outline: Revamped the FluxStore shopping app using Flutter and Firebase, executing a comprehensive redesign of the user interface to enhance the shopping experience and boost sales by 40% within 3 months.

Technical Skills: I redesigned the application and implemented extensive configuration changes, adding new features tailored to meet specific user requirements.

Achievements: Google Play - AppStore

Project title: Pet Planet

Project Outline: Revamped the FluxStore shopping app using Flutter and Firebase, executing a comprehensive redesign of the user interface to enhance the shopping experience and boost sales by 40% within 3 months.

Technical Skills :I redesigned the application and implemented extensive configuration changes, adding new features tailored to meet specific user requirements.

Achievements: Google Play - AppStore

Project title: Jumla center

Project Outline: Revamped the FluxStore shopping app using Flutter and Firebase, executing a comprehensive redesign of the user interface to enhance the shopping experience and boost sales by 40% within 3 months.

Technical Skills: I redesigned the application and implemented extensive configuration changes, adding new features tailored to meet specific user requirements.

Achievements: Play - AppStore

Education

Damanhour University, Egypt Bachelor Of Arts

Jan 2017

Skills

Programming Languages: dart

Frameworks/Libraries: Flutter - Material Design - MVVM - MVP - S.O.L.I.D - JSON - Git - Retrofit - Firebase

- RestApi -SQLite -Maps - Notifications - Adobe XD - Android - Architectural Pattern - ,

Bloc (state management) - Provider (state management)

Operating Systems: Linux/Unix, Windows

Language skills: Fluent in Arabic. - / Good in written and spoken English.